Everyone you and I know
is hustling hard to survive the incoming
wave of AI,
yourself and even Declan here. Declan
is my editor,
but he's also running his own
business,
and you should probably be a bit worried
that AI's just going to take
everything that you do, do it better,
and put you out of a job before you're
even
25, correct?
So now you're in a bit of a panic in your
life where you're like, "I need to make
money now within the next three years,
or I'll never have the opportunity to use
my
skills to make money." He's nodding.
So in this video,
we're going to talk about how to operate a
one-man business,
because technically you're a one-man
business.
I was for a long time a one-man business,
then I had to hire you to help me out
with stuff. But I became very profitable,
got a lot of green light signals early
on, built a brand,
and I didn't hire people till maybe six
years in.
So this video is for you.
It's also kind of for him,
and what's good is he's
probably going to ask me the questions
you're thinking of as we film it.
So running and operating a one-person
business is not difficult at
all. If anything, it's so much easier,
because managing people is just energy,
it's
organization,
and I think a lot of people
are kind of saying to people,
"Oh, you should get someone to do this,
get someone to do that." No.
In the onset,
you want to do everything yourself.
You want to keep it tight-knit, and also,
the one thing that you were asking me
just before we started recording, Declan,
was about getting profitable early.
Now, as a one-man band,
you only need to cover your own bills.
If you come out the gates with staff,
you've got to pay a whole load of other
costs
before you actually get afloat.
I think it's also like you're probably
doing something else as your full-time
job,
so you need to find a way
that you can start making it somewhat
profitable early.
Yeah. And we're going to go through that.
So those of you that watched any of my
videos before, we've got a four-stage
framework,
and you can't jump steps on the framework.
The first one is socials,
then it's going to be squeeze,
then it's going to be
sell, then it's going to be scale.
We're going to go through
that downstairs in a
second. And in essence,
I'm going to teach you
that you don't need big teams.
You don't need to DM strangers.
You don't need to be doing sales calls.
I'm saying that the majority of people
giving you advice are lying to you.
Ten years ago,
I was working as a personal trainer in a
budget gym in Bracknell,
living at home with my parents
and snorting too much cocaine at the
weekends.
Now I run multiple seven-figure
businesses. But the "Sunday Times"...
Oh, no, one of them's fallen down. Oh, no,
one of my "Sunday Times"
number one best-selling books has fallen
over.
You can't see that in the frame,
by the way. It's too high.
What, is it not even in it? Well,
you'll have to take my word for it then,
people,
won't you? Number one bestseller,
by the way, not top 10.
Some people, "Oh,
I'm a bestselling author." Top 10, sure.
Not number one, though, were you?
And I believe that the majority of you
watching
this video should be able to make it to a
million dollars in revenue on your own,
but we're not going to go that far.
We're just going to start at 10K a month
and
what that looks like.
So the first thing we need to look at
is what I call the
hybrid advantage, and for
that to make most sense,
we're going to go downstairs.
Something very important
when it comes to growing online
is what I call the hybrid
advantage.
And not hybrid as in the people
that like run and lift and they're like,
"Oh, I'm a hybrid athlete.
I do HYROX." None of that.
Do you do HYROX?
You look like you do HYROX.
So a good example for this would be
personal training,
and we're also going to use
Declan as an example here. So Declan,
at the moment, has got one
main pool of income, which
is working for me, but his
aspirations are actually to have a second
pool of income.
And I could be naive as an employee
and go, "He's just going to work for me
forever." But actually, everyone
that works for me eventually will leave me
from
what skills they learn, I hope.
So let's say that's you there.
Another example of this would be people
that are PTs and then
people that want to PT online.
So in the onset, what's good is for
Declan, the amount
that I pay him covers his Maslow hierarchy
of
needs,
so he can afford to pay for his rent,
his food, his gym, his
clothes, et cetera.
Most personal trainers should be looking
at their business the
same. Yeah, it might not be sexy
that you're not in Bali
and you're working in a
gym and you're having to count people's
reps and sets, but this first part of the
scale here is about getting enough money
just to pay the bills.
Because once this is covered,
you can relax and go, "Okay, if it takes
one year or three years or five years,
it's fine." The issue is that there
are some
people, even people in my mentorship,
that come straight to this side and go, "I
want to PT online.
I've only got four clients.
How can I get to 20 clients?" I go, "Well,
what are you doing at the moment?"
"Nothing.
I'm just fully online." It's a bit of a
scary place to be in.
Same way that if Declan quit today,
he could run his own online business, but
is it going to be enough to cover his
bills? Probably not.
If you go straight into this,
the worst thing is stress.
Because with you covering your bills here,
if you have an email marketing email
that bombs, it's not going to feel great,
but it's not the end of the world.
If you're over here
and you build a course and no one buys it,
it's not the end of
the world. Also, knowing
that all your bills are paid for in tier
one means that you can have a few weeks
off, or you can try some new things,
or you
can do some high-risk stuff over here.
So it's really important
that people realize
that they want to have over
here the day job.
So you might be an accountant for a
business that you're
employed.
You could be a physio in someone else's
practice.
This is the thing
that you're going to build up.
This is the thing that's going to pay the
bills.
Now, for those of you, unfortunately,
you want to go straight into number two.
You want to be an online personal trainer.
You want to be Insta-famous and mega-rich.
I get it.
Or you want to have your own business
or whatever. Can't stress this enough.
There is so much of an advantage
if you just get what you want here from a
job, and then at the stage
that you're making enough money,
you're going to go
across and do this full-time.
So let's think about it this way.
Let's say I pay Declan 10K a month,
which isn't far off. Cool.
The reality is that
when he starts his online thing over here,
even
though 10K might not be his earning
potential, it's enough to pay his bills,
pay
his taxes, or whatever. The reality
is that over here, these things
are going to
take time to build up. And again,
if you were to start just here
and trying to
make a living from this,
it's too much stress.
It's just too much pressure on yourself to
perform, and this is where people get
very overwhelmed and upset and whatever.
So with Declan having his job here,
if you made $100 this month with your side
gig, you'd probably be pretty chuffed.
But if it's five months in
and you're only making $800,
although you could be
quite disappointed with it,
you're not going to be in a position where
you have to
pack it all in and go do whatever.
The issue is that if Declan doesn't have
this job here, the primary income,
by this point,
he's going to have to fuck off
back to a job in corporate
or recruitment or whatever.
So again,
Declan would rather be at home right now
doing his own thing, making his
own money,
but he's here working for me for this
exact reason, because he's got to
pay the bills until he builds this up in
the background.
How much are you making a month actually
at the moment from-
$300 a month.
Oh, really? Just in views? Cool.
So you're making $300 per month. Is
that USD?
Come on, mate.
I know you're back in the UK with me,
but come on. Come on, mate.
Let's go followers. For the business?
Yeah.
Is that Instagram or-
YouTube.
YouTube. Mate,
that's actually really good.
Fuck,
you might be leaving me sooner than I
thought.
Instagram,
do you use Instagram at all for business,
really?
Even though you've got it.
Do you know how many monthly views you're
getting?
About 80,000.
Fucking hell. Yeah, that's pretty good.
4,000 on the email list.
Let that sink in, right? Because there
are personal trainers here
that I work with.
There's one guy I
was just having a fucking argument with in
the Discord.
In the last year,
he's grown his email list by 180 people.
180 people.
More people heard my car parking it in the
gym
today than you've got on your email list.
That's sick. Cool.
Now, the good thing here
is you're absolutely backing up my exact
point.
You are building up the most important
part of your business here, and it's not
paying that much.
And how long have you been running this
business?
Five months.
Cool. This is great. This
is everything you need.
This backs up my point exactly, that
if you are in a hybrid position...
How do you feel about this at the moment?
Pretty good,
but I just need to make the course,
and then I either feel great or I
feel like shit. Let's see.
So Declan feels pretty good with this,
and do you know what?
I feel pretty good about that with you.
But how do you feel when I take this away?
Fuck.
Not good. Cool.
So I don't care how fucking sexy you are,
how much
muscles you got,
or how good your fucking butt looks in a
pair of leggings.
To do both at the same time
is a massive advantage.
Do not neglect that because you just don't
need the stress.
You've probably got a number in your head
where you're going to make so much from
this that you'll probably go to part-time
and then you'll leave.
Or what you'll do is you'll go, "James,
this is how this situation's going to
change. I'm still going to do your edit,
but instead of me doing it, my agency's
going to do it,
and my agency's going to bill you,"
and whatever.
Then you're going to hire people to do it
underneath you. Okay, cool.
Now, the second thing
that we're going to talk about after the
hybrid advantage,
everything you know about social media
is wrong.
Whatever amount of followers you have,
the golden aim is to get
20% of them onto your email list.
So what are you at before you said? 7,000?
4,000.
You've got over 50% of your fucking
followers on your email list.
How did you get so many?
Free lots.
What do you mean free lots?
So I gave away free lots.
Oh, free lots. I thought you said...
So as a percentage of your audience,
that's fucking incredible. So that's good.
So you're going to build a course.
What's great here is even if 1%,
how much are you going to sell the course
for?
Start at $99 and then just raise it every
couple of-
Cool.
So as far as the amount of followers to
the amount of people on your email
list, the percentage I love is 20%.
You're absolutely smashing that.
But the one thing
that everyone doesn't really tell you,
I'm kind of jumping a step
here, but we'll get into it,
is I think 1% conversions is good.
Some people out there go, "Oh,
only 1% of people bought my program." I'm
like,
"Mate, that's fucking great." So
if you were to see 1% of yours
buy,
that's going to be 40 purchases at $99.
Call it $100.
It's going to be four grand straight away
just from that first
initial push. Then not to mention, if
that was 1% per email, you could
probably squeeze through maybe 10K from
your launch.
Then with that money,
you could run some paid ads,
you could grow your audience,
you could make more content.
For four grand, yeah.
Anyway, we'll come back to
that bit in a second.
So people out there,
they're getting depressed.
Again, 1% for some people,
they might think that it's
a really depressing amount of sales,
but if you have enough email addresses and
enough of your followers on your email
list, that 1% is absolutely fine.
So I don't think there's ever been a point
in my business where
more than 1% of my audience
are doing business with me.
Even in the business mentorship,
we got 50,000 on YouTube,
we haven't got 5,000 in
the Discord, so six, seven. Yeah, cool.
All right, we'll skip that bit.
So although it can be really complex at
times for people, so many people on social
media are saying you need to do so much.
But this ratio, for any of you
that kind of want to do an audit,
you want to stress
test your business at the moment.
What percentage of my followers
are on my email
list? Now, if this is at 10%,
it's not bad, right? I can accept that.
It's not too bad. But straight away,
you've got two places you can put your
attention, because a video
that gets email addresses
is very different to a video
that gets you followers. So for instance,
my focus to grow this bit is going to be
using good hooks.
It's going to be doing loads of research.
It's going to be looking at trends.
It's going to be doing all the kinds of
things that are going to get new people
onto my account.
But then trying to get email addresses
is going
to be a completely different type of sales
content.
So whatever you're going to put out at the
moment, you ask yourself, "Right, I'm at
10%. What's more important,
more followers or more emails?" Probably
more emails.
Think of followers as planting crops.
Think of emails as harvesting those crops.
So planting the crops, 10 months later,
harvest them.
You can't really do both at the same time.
I would say this video
is actually more about getting followers
in, because our
packaging,
we're talking about going from naught to
10K.
We spoke about the single-man business.
This is probably going to draw in more
people from a different audience.
So if this video was about emails,
I would've given you a call to action way
earlier, because
when it comes to getting lead magnets, I
typically won't put them too early in the
video.
Yeah, so let's say-
But wouldn't the argument be you should
try to capture as many people as possible?
Yeah, you've got that,
but so let's say this
is a typical retention graph and
video. If emails
were the most important thing,
I'd have a lead magnet here,
here, here. But this video,
I actually think is one of the
less planned, more talk alongs,
more whatever, where I would say probably
80% or 90% of people of this video
are going to leave because they're going
to go,
"Ah, this isn't a well,
perfectly created video.
This guy's just chatting to his fucking
videographer.
He's just chatting shit." So let's say all
these people up until this point leave.
This video for me is actually about these
guys.
So it's like qualified leads in a way.
Yeah. So,
and you remember we said 1% of people
was pretty good.
For this, if 98% of people leave,
the 2% that are remaining at the
end, I could just look down the camera
and say, "Buy my fucking course,
you piece of shit. Oh, you're poor
and ugly.
I can't help you be less ugly,
but I can help you be less poor.
So yeah, you little piece of shit,
click that link." That's what I'd say to
them,
Declan, at the end. Don't click it now.
I've got a fucking video to teach you.
Why are you being like that?
So this video really for me is
that core 2% of
people that are going to go,
"Jesus Christ,
this guy's content's really helping me
out." Because even just hearing me say
that 98% of people can fuck off
and die, that makes them go, "Oh,
do you know what?
That's so refreshing to hear." Because
most people online are telling you
that you
should suck off every single person
watching your video.
Do you know how many people would've got
their backs up and left at the thing that
I just said there? You know
when I condescendingly looked down the
lens and said to
them, "Buy my shit or you can fuck off
and die." Most people would've thought,
"No
way am I paying that guy."
But the people that are left after this,
they're the
ones, Declan. They're the ones. All right,
getting distracted.
It's only supposed to be a three-minute
video.
You're still going to be able to make this
a reel, yeah?
You're still going to make this a reel?
Okay, we're going back upstairs.
So just before we get into the exacts of
how you'd get from zero to
$10,000,
first thing we need to look into
is there are a lot of you watching this
who are trying to work your way towards
that amount, and you don't think that you
should suck at things.
So I'm going to quickly show you through
some YouTube
accounts of people that used to suck.
Actually, I tell you what,
Damian Talks Money is here.
I haven't proofed any of these beforehand.
Let's go have a look.
So when you look at his videos,
we can very quickly look at his most
popular
videos. 1.2 million, 904K, 742K.
Wow, this guy's a fucking G. But
if we go back to his oldest videos,
first of all,
he looks a little bit sinister in these
thumbs. So look at this.
Look at this guy. Overexposed,
color grading's completely out.
Got some basic animations on the side.
Very
different to the stuff he does now.
He's just got images
that he screenshots across the screen.
It's not quite what you would think.
And again,
a lot of people do do what I'm doing
and go back to the oldest ones, so
that's why the views will be a little bit
higher.
But again, we can see
that these videos here
are quite a bit worse than the
ones he's putting out now.
I would say this isn't a terrible example.
Another one, Ed Lawrence,
my YouTube sensei, who
crushes at the moment.
If we go back to his older channel,
Film Booth, I like to do
this as an exercise for my students as
well.
The guy that taught me how to make YouTube
videos, again, used to make the worst
YouTube videos you've ever seen,
with some of the worst packaging you've
ever seen.
But let's go back even further than that.
Marques Brownlee, who is a tech reviewer,
20.7
million subscribers.
If we go back to his oldest videos,
you've got a kid.
A kid talking you through stuff.
Look at this.
So every single person
that we see online at one point used to
suck. And again,
if I take you up to the top, he's made 1.7
thousand videos. Now,
let's do some basic maths, and for
basic maths, we're going to ChatGPT.
1.7 thousand videos on YouTube.
That person
posts one every three days, which
is a lot.
How long have they been posting for?
One video every three days on YouTube
is quite punchy.
14 years of posting every three days.
That's insane.
So another person we could use,
Modern Wisdom.
I could sometimes look at these podcasts
and go, "Oh, why is this guy getting more
views than me?" We could go back to some
of his oldest videos.
I wonder if he's unlisted some of them,
actually.
Again,
we go back to one of Chris's oldest videos
where he is...
There's only one microphone between two
people.
His thumbnails used to be absolutely
bloody awful.
Terrible.
But here's the point I want to draw your
attention to.
Chris has 4.1 thousand videos.
4.1 thousand videos.
So for some of you out there,
if you go take a long,
hard look at your Instagram,
you've done 180 posts
and you're crying about results
that you haven't got. You're on YouTube,
you've posted 30 videos across three
years,
and you're crying about the results you
don't have.
Let me have a little look here.
If I look at nearly 5,000 fucking
Instagram posts.
So for those of you that
are out there that maybe suck at content,
everyone fucking
sucks. Some people put in the work,
grafting and growing their audience,
and some
people don't.
And if you think you're in the camp of
people that doesn't have to
turn up that many times,
and you think you can just get lucky
and get to a million
followers within 1,000 posts, fuck off,
you fucking delusional piece of
shit. So you suck. We suck. We all suck.
I'm nearly a black belt in jujitsu.
Guess what?
I was fucking awful at white belt,
and it took me nine years to get better.
If you think there
is any way you're going to circumnavigate
that, you're dreaming.
Okay, one of the next stages
that we're going to need,
we spoke about social media,
but this isn't really a video on content
creation.
This is more about the money-making of it.
We could do a whole another video about
content creation, or if you've got any
topics that you want, just comment below.
So the next stage is going to be email
marketing.
Now, I do suggest
that you have some form of email marketing
segmentation for when
people sign up. For instance,
say someone joins my email list today
and it's a
Friday afternoon and I'm not going to work
over the weekend.
I don't want that person to sign up,
then have crickets
and not get anything from
me for two days,
then they get an email on Monday.
So I might set up some email automations
that are in place.
So if you look in the description to this
video, there should be a link that says
30 Ways in 30 Days.
I want you to click that,
I want you to sign up to it, and I
want you to steal it.
So what will happen is,
every single day over those 30 days,
I will give you a little bit of a nugget
in an email that takes less than 60
seconds to read. And the idea is, again,
that 90% of people go, "Oh, that's pretty
good. Never thought of that."
And they get to the end, never buy it.
But for 10% of people,
as they're reading them,
they're getting nurtured without
even realizing, and
when they get to the end of the sequence,
they go, "Shit.
If I learned all that for free,
imagine what I'd get if I paid
that person." So
again,
rather than me going on about how we
should structure the emails, where they
should be aligned,
where the call to action should be,
why there wasn't a call to
action in the first two days,
and all the rest of them did,
and why the call to
action's in the PS, just copy mine.
It's much easier. Was that a lead magnet?
Yes, it was. Now,
the next thing I'm going to tell you
about, for the very few
remaining people
that have made it this far in the video
because you're not
offended by the way
that I've spoken to you is,
I've spoken a lot before about why
sales calls are dead. I think in 2020,
people needed more information, and
people were sat at home,
and they wanted to do Zoom calls.
They don't anymore.
And the pandemic protocol of making sales
isn't the same as today.
What people need is information.
I've still got people now
that I work with that
are really scared to let go of sales
calls.
They go, "Oh,
but sales calls have worked for me,
and I'm really worried to let go
of them." My question to you is this:
what is someone getting from a sales call
that they couldn't get from your website?
Because if someone arrives to your website
and they read it and they don't buy, but
if they jump on a call with you for an
hour and they do buy, you're obviously
giving them something on the call
that they're not getting from your
website.
So you can keep continuing to do that
and give up hours of your time for people
that get to the end of the call and say,
"I need to think about it." Or you could
just make your fucking landing page on
your website better.
Now, again, the language there
is a bit interjectable.
So this is a landing page,
and the reason I call it a landing page
is this has one
purpose, and it's to get people to buy.
A website would have About Me, Contact,
FAQs, all of that
rubbish.
You might even have some socials links at
the bottom, which again, I think
is fucking moronic because the last thing
you want someone to do is get to the
bottom and click on YouTube. So again,
there's going to be a link to this
template
here where you can basically copy my
highly converting landing page
structure. But the reason for this is,
let's bring it back to Declan for a
second.
Right now, 4,000 people on his email list,
he sends them an offer.
If he then wants to do sales calls,
there's now a barrier between the 4,000
people
on his list and money appearing in his
bank account.
I would much rather
that he spent a few days putting together
a highly converting
landing page so that every time he hits
that list of 4,000 people, his diary
doesn't become fuller.
Because him being a hybrid business at the
moment, if Declan
now has to do 10 sales calls a week,
my edits are going to get shitter,
he's going
to get fired, and he's going to lose
that first pillar of income that holds him
afloat.
Or his life's going to become miserable
because he's now got to get home
from working for me all day to then sit on
three hours of sales calls for two
people to buy and one person to waste his
time.
It just doesn't make sense for people to
need to jump on a call with him when he
could just have a page that they land on.
And this is the question I'll ask him,
which I haven't preemptively asked him
now.
Would you rather, Declan,
two out of three people
that you do a sales call
with buy your product,
but the sales calls are half an hour?
Or would you rather,
rather it being two out of three people,
it's now two out of
six people,
so the ratio of people buying is halved,
but you don't have
to talk to them? So the answer here
is that he's just said,
occasionally hearing on
the mic,
is he would much rather just make more
content.
And those three hours you spend on the
call, you could spend one hour filming,
two
hour editing, and boom,
you're just bringing more people in.
And this is the thing
that I don't think people realize.
You could tell me
that your sales calls
are way more successful than your
landing page, and I'd go,
"I still don't care." I would rather the
worst-performing
landing page be there. Because
if you've got 4,000 emails now,
it's not going to be
long till you're at 10,000.
It's not going to be long till you're at
50,000.
And eventually,
you're going to get to the point where you
go, "I can't do the
sales calls," or,
"I'm going to have to pay someone else to
do them," or whatever.
I think it just makes so much more sense
to have a system that
works so you can stay doing what you're
good at and that you enjoy.
The content, for instance. Right now,
I'm enjoying this way more.
And this one hour of work Can reach
thousands of
people,
versus a sales call can only really reach
one person.
So copy my emails, copy my landing page.
It's quite simple, pretty much.
I say tiny bit of branding. I hate it
when people put their logo there because
essentially your logo doesn't do anything.
If yours says Declan Jenkinson Film,
I'm like, "Cool." Above the fold,
so where the
marker is,
is the first part of the screen I'm going
to see.
I'm like,
"It didn't do anything." I didn't see your
logo and go, "Fucking hell.
Where do I pay?" The heading
and the subheading, it could say,
"Learn to color
grade and stop wasting your money on
LUTs." Straight away I go, "Fuck,
I am wasting
my money on LUTs." Whatever it is. VSL,
introduction to yourself, the program,
what
you've created, how it helps them,
how it would change their life, pricing,
different things, how to pay. And again,
you get that from the description.
But the idea of jumping on calls with
people.
I fucking hate phone calls,
to be perfectly honest with you.
And again, you should too. And again,
if someone is going to jump on a call,
they
should pay for it.
That's the way I see it.
And again,
I think there's something beautiful about
the fact that if you watch
this video and you click on my business
mentorship page and you don't feel
compelled to buy, fine. Your course
is going to help people with color
grading.
My course helps people make more money.
And if you need a fucking phone call to
buy it, then fuck off and join someone
else's program. It sounds mad, but
if you're already such a needy fucker
before we've even got to the mentorship,
I don't care.
Someone's like, "Okay. And Declan, how
is this course going to help me?" Or
whatever. Now, there are some people
that will need some form of call.
Let's say you run an accountancy firm,
and you deal with businesses that make
between 1 and 500K a year
or between $1 and $5 million a year,
whatever.
But even then, I would say to them,
"You pay the money, you join,
or you apply.
Then in the onboarding call
if you're not right for it,
I'll refund you the money."
Because then even if you're going to pay
the same amount of money, and that's the
only onboarding process I'd have.
Some personal trainers are like, "Oh,
but James,
I need to call them to make sure they're a
right fit for my business."
I'm like, "All right. Why not?
Charge them the money,
make them pay." When you do
the onboarding call, if they go, "Oh,
sorry, Susie, I'm really sorry,
but this is a
skiing program,
and you don't have any legs,
I'm going to refund you.
And Susie,
you probably shouldn't have bought because
you haven't got any legs." So
it's one of those.
I would rather money was in the bank,
few people got refunded,
than the alternative.
So let's say you run a higher ticket
course,
which is a handheld editing master class,
where it's 10K.
You get full access to all the courses,
and over 10 weeks, you do a one-to-one
where you can watch them edit
and give them tricks or whatever.
You just say to someone, "It's 10K.
In the first call, if I realize
that you have no idea what you're doing,
I'll just
refund you." Because let's say someone
buys your color grading course and then
goes, "Hey, mate,
I've not got a laptop." Rather than being
like, "Oh, why'd you
buy it?" Because if you don't refund
that person,
they'll go to all corners of the
internet. They'll troll you.
They'll chat shit.
Mate,
so we're doing the Nutonic variety packs
at the moment.
Some people will come back and go, "James,
I don't like this flavor," and I'll
refund them a quarter of the pack.
Some people go, "I didn't like these two
flavors." I'll refund half the pack.
This week,
from where we've gone a bit wider with the
offer, some people go, "I
didn't like any of the flavors." I know
they're lying.
I know they're lying,
but I refund them because I would rather
be the mug than
have one psychopath
that fucking then goes to
Amazon and gives it a one-star review,
and then they talk to a newspaper and
say they got ill.
I would rather have them mug me off than
the other way around.
And that person that bought the course
and doesn't have a laptop, in sense, has
mugged you off a little bit. But so what?
Just eat the loss of four cents
that you lose on the Stripe transaction
fee.
Okay, we're going to go downstairs,
do the last part of how we're going to get
to
10K a month. Let's do it. Let's run it.
Okay,
so we're going to look at the 10K per
month running your online
business. First things first,
let's break that down.
Let's say it's 30 days a month.
So we need to find $333
per day. So your course was $99.
Do you think that's a good starting point
as well?
For a $99 course? Yeah.
100%.
100%. Nah, because if that course
is worth $199, you sell it for $99,
it's fine.
But because you've got tier one,
you're way better off undercharging.
Because again,
when I started the business mentorship,
it was 800 US dollars,
lifetime access. Those people
that paid me the least, Kathryn Sargeants,
the Ryan
Moats,
Eric,
who's got fucking millions of followers,
those people are the
ones now that go out their way to give me
the best testimonials.
And again,
you can afford to undercharge because you
have the
first primary level of income.
And for people to join and know they got a
fucking good deal makes them feel happy.
So again, that's fine.
Even if it's worth 1,000,
starting off with that is great.
Then also,
when you do start putting up prices,
when we construct your landing
page, you could say,
"Over 3,000 people have learned to grade
using this system,"
as an appeal to authority to make them
think, "Well, if everyone's doing it, I
should be doing it." So let's say you need
3.5 sales a day.
I think with the emails now I'm getting
around 60 a day.
Wow, okay. So 3.5 sales a day, 60 new
emails.
And that's from two pieces of evergreen
YouTube content.
It just keeps getting new people.
Okay. And those are coming from evergreen.
So that means that they're old videos
that are showing you leads, which is the
probably best benefit of using YouTube.
Okay, that's great.
So if we wanted to get,
I'm just going to double-check my maths
here.
If I needed three
and a half people to buy, and there's
60 of them,
what percentage of those people do I need
to buy?
I get ChatGPT to help me with everything
now.
But it might not even be correct,
but it doesn't matter. Yeah, cool. 5.8%.
So you would need a 5.8% success rate
on the people coming in evergreen to hit
that quota.
And I would say that that
is way too punchy,
and that's completely fine.
So when we're working towards that 10K,
to be short of it is
fine in the onset because at the moment,
this is your current system.
But the other thing is your business
is in its infancy, and if I was to say,
post how many videos a week do you do at
the moment?
Once a month.
So if you were to increase your frequency
to one a week, there's going to come a
point where you're getting 600 new emails
a day.
And then at 600 emails a day,
suddenly that would be a
0.58% success rate
that you would need to make the money.
Does that make sense?
Yeah. Cool. So straight away,
all we need to do is to get the 10K,
we need to look
at the amount we need to make per day.
Then from the amount we need to make per
day, three and a half sales isn't that
scary or that difficult. But now
if we go back to the strategy of what
that could
look like. So we've got a funnel here.
We spoke about it before.
So socials, mostly YouTube,
which I think is the best place for
this because people that
are interested in what it is
that you're doing are going
to have content served to them.
We could start doing some Instagram
and some TikTok
or whatever, but for the time being,
I think this is completely fine. Socials.
So at the moment, we're getting
60 emails per day from evergreen, which
is sick.
Also, it's worth noting
that as you add more content to the top of
the funnel,
that's going to improve.
I would then say to yourself,
how many community posts
do you do a month?
Cool.
So you could just do some community posts
that are like,
whether it's talking about your offer,
whether it's talking about your email
list.
You could even schedule a community post
about once a week going, "Here is a
problem that people have with editing.
Give them some kind of solution.
If you want to hear more from me,
join my email list." For your email list,
when I
join it, do I get automations?
You get 10 days of-
Lovely.
So you've got the 10-day automation
already in there.
38% open rate, that's great.
Few responses.
So already, your system,
how many videos a month would you say?
Very bad.
0.5? 0.35.
So you're posting four times per year, and
you're already not actually
that far off your quota.
How much would you say you're making a
month? Say 400. 300, fine.
That's all right.
But considering that you're not putting
much in the top, if you were to go from
that to one a month-
Yeah
...
you could potentially 4X everything that's
happening over here.
See,
my thing is I've been stalling making the
content, trying to overplan the
course,
when I should just get the course out,
and then I can put all my attention
into it.
So, where your bottleneck is,
is this point.
Yeah.
So we have the social,
we have the squeeze, we have the sell.
Now,
because you haven't got something to sell,
you've not been feeding the top of
the funnel,
which is completely fine because your
offer.
But when the course is finished, this
is going to be the $99 course.
And then is there going to be a
high-ticket offer?
Probably not.
Oh, yeah. Fine. Cool.
No need for the high-ticket offer.
So we're going to have that.
We're going to build the course.
So then I don't think
that selling 100 products a month is that
difficult.
It would be less than 10K a month,
$99 products,
100 sales a month I don't think is crazy,
considering you're already getting this
from doing it pretty part-time.
So for instance, at this point,
I don't think we
need to introduce another offer.
What would actually be the next thing to
look at
would be to scale. So eventually,
once you hit 10K a
month,
you're probably then going to become
partially limited with what you would
do next. So for scale,
what do you think you would do to grow
the business?
Would it be about more socials,
more emails,
more offers,
or do you reckon at some point you would
start to build a team?
I've spoken to-
Keep the team for as long as possible.
Cool,
which goes into the point of the video.
You want to keep it simple.
So let's humor this for a second, though.
I think that I would say you would create
some form of edit
agency. Now,
the reason I would say this is,
I would then
say you become, let's say, the director.
You would then have editors,
and then I reckon you would have some
strategists, maybe one.
You would then have a big established
YouTube
channel.
Then I think you would go into business to
business.
So at the moment, these people,
they're going to buy your course.
Would you say they're consumers? Cool.
So I would say this is B2B,
business to consumer. They're hobbyists,
like you say.
I reckon then the next step would go B2B,
because you help these people color
grade, that's great. But
if you help another business become more
profitable, get
more views,
if you can then help another business with
the funnel.
Because this is the meta, this
is the point of the whole video,
that really I'm
trying to make the point of.
You mastering this process here in your
spare
time whilst working for me will make you
very efficient at understanding what
content works, what emails convert,
what offers get sales.
Then you create this as your lifestyle
business.
So this is going to be the part
that means you can travel the brought to
you by
Vuitton. the world, and
that you can enjoy yourself or whatever.
And you could ride that for three,
four years.
And then it comes to a point where you go,
"Fuck, I really want a Ferrari.
I really want an 812 Superfast with a
Novitec exhaust." Great choice.
So once you get to that point,
you then would start to leverage your idea
of how
you would potentially scale.
Because very difficult to sell
anything above that. But the agency,
where you consider you've got to hire
people,
this is the bit where you can go to
another business, and you could say, "It's
$15,000 for three months."
And straight away, people go, "Why are you
charging $15,000 for three months?"
Because if you go into most businesses
and you say, "Here's the idea.
I'm going to have two editors
that work around the
clock.
I'm going to have a strategist that's
going to do all our packaging."
Because this is actually what's happening
at the moment for me.
At the moment,
I come up with the ideas for the videos.
You edit them.
Then we have Ollie as the strategist.
And the beautiful part of this is,
after today's video,
I walk away to go train
jujitsu. You edit the video.
You send the screen grabs to Ollie.
Ollie does the title and the thumbnails.
Ollie then tests the titles
and thumbnails to find out
which works for me best.
Which means I can go off
and be a director in other businesses like
Nutonic or
whatever.
You can continue to edit the videos,
and Ollie can continue to learn what
my audience wants. Now, the beauty of
that is, is that going to pay back in
one video 15 grand?
Are we going to make 15 grand from this
video?
Maybe, maybe not.
But over the course of three, six,
12 months,
understanding that process for me
is what benefits my business to make
enough
money that I wouldn't squint at $15,000.
So that's where I think the scale would
be.
The only issue there is
that would add a lot more stress to your
life, because if
you... What even is that? Fucking dogs.
Would you fucking mind, lads?
I'm trying to run a business here.
I did get pepto's in my eyeballs. Oops.
[laughs]
All right. I'm closing the last minute,
all right?
Please buy my product so I can get richer
friends.
So now,
this is the point that's important.
This part, the lifestyle business, this
is the fun part.
This is the part
that you can do it on your own.
You can run your own business.
You can be stress-free.
You can travel the world.
You enjoy the shit out of that, Declan.
That naught to 10K per month,
when you do the numbers,
isn't actually that
crazy. If you were to post more videos,
you would get more emails, where you'd
still at 1% conversion rate.
Because think of it this, right?
If you're doing four videos a year,
you could easily do 40 videos a year.
Like, easily. So that means
that your 60 people a day would be
600 people a day.
If 1% of those buy your shit, that's six
people a day.
That takes you well beyond your sales
target.
That actually takes you to 20K per month
at a 1% success rate.
Then-
I might double the price of the course at
some point too.
Yeah,
you could also just double the price of
the course.
Yeah, fucking didn't even think of that.
Fuck,
I might get you to do the next video.
Then the scale part would be the part in
the future.
When you've made good connections,
you know people within your network,
this is
actually where I think your play would be.
I think you would say to me, "James,
I'm going to hire another editor.
I'm going to hire Ollie full-time under
me, and you're now going to pay my agency
for what you currently pay both of us."
That's where I think the play would be.
That's why I've joked with you
and Ollie having the boys.
Yeah. I just wonder if
that responsibility is something
that I want.
Well, this is the part, right?
Because at the moment,
the responsibility is tough.
The other thing that's fucked is
if I don't give you work,
you cost me money
without making me money.
Yeah.
So if I don't give you good ideas,
you cost me money without making money.
So that's the stage that people rush to.
They wish their life away
and don't realize how fun this part is.
Yeah.
So run-
That part sounds sick to me
... running the business on your own
is great,
but there's going to come a point
where-
I don't want money
... 20K a month isn't enough.
And the hard thing is, right now,
looking at 20K a
month, you think,
"That'd be amazing." Until you get to 20K
a month, and you
go, "Well, if I want the car,
and I want the house near the beach,
and I want to
fly business class,
it's not enough." Cool.
There's links in the description.
If you want to work with me,
it's like three and a half K,
which seems like a lot.
It's not. Everyone else charges way more.
That Callaway lad on YouTube,
seven grand for his, then 1,900 a month.
Just his blueprint is like 6K. Yeah,
you make good videos, bro,
but I'm pretty sure all you do
is make videos. No offense.
I'm not here beefing Callaway.
I'm just saying, where
are your best-selling books?
Where's your 911 GT3?
Where's your eight-figure drinks business?
Where's your world's biggest coaching app?
Where's your selling out Hammersmith Polo?
I'm not being bitter. I'm just saying.
Either you're overcharging
or I'm undercharging.
It could be me, if I'm completely honest.
And one of the reasons could be because I
already have loads of money.
I don't know.
But we could sell Nutonic in a few years.
I'll have so much money
that I'll be so expensive.
And this is really the golden zone,
where I'm poor enough
that I still need your
business, but rich enough
that I won't rip you off.
Because I'll be honest, when
that payslip comes through,
in a few years' time, when
Coca-Cola buy us,
I ain't even talking to anyone for less
than 100K.
I'll be like, "Oh, you want a bit of help?
Pay the money. Wire the money.
100K or don't even bother." I wouldn't
even talk to my mates for less than 10
grand.
[laughs] Check the links in the
description.
Like I said, I can't help you
if you're ugly, but I can help you
if you want to
make more money.
[clapping]
Brought to you by Vuitton